Guide to the Paul Leicester Ford Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1736-1902; Series IV; 2; 0.63 linear_feet
  - Periodicals containing articles about Paul Leicester Ford, 1890-1897; 2 (Box 23)
    Related Materials
    Also stored in: Box 28 (Oversize)
  - An Authentic Detail of Particulars Relative to the Late Duchess of Kingston. (London: printed for G. Kearsley, at Johnson's Head, 1788) (Box 23)
  - The Trial of Elizabeth Duchess Dowager of Kingston for Bigamy, Before the Right Honourable The House of Peers, in Westminster-Hall in Full Parliament. London: Printed for Charles Bathurst, in Fleet-Street, 1776., 1776 April 15
  - The Library Journal, 1888 January-February (Box 23)
  - The Library Journal (continued), 1890 January (Box 23)
  - The Library Journal (continued), 1890 March (Box 23)
  - The Library Journal (continued), 1891 January (Box 23)
  - The St. James's Register: or, Taste A-La-Mode. (London: Printed and Sold by Edmund Cook, near Ludgate-Hill, 1736) (Box 23)
  - "The Washington Centenary", 1889 April (Box 23)
    Accompanied by badge worn by Gordon L. Ford as Vice Chairman of the Art and Exhibition Committee; badge includes commemorative medal
  - "Whitefieldiana" - manuscript notes or draft (Box 24)
  - "Ye merrie songs of ye disciples of Benjamin Franklin" - event program and booklet, 1902 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous printed ephemera, 3 (Box 24)
  - Adverstising materials for writings and plays, orchestra parts
- 1976-1977 Addition, 1814-1900; Series V; 2; 1.25 linear_feet + 2 art
  Unarranged.
  The addition consists of writings, correspondence, items printed by Ford on his private press including his 1876 "Webster Genealogy," related material concerning Noah Webster, and personal papers. It also includes notable portraits of Noah Webster and his wife, and portraits of Ford and his popular character Janice Meredith.
  - Autobiographical sketch, typescript, and clippings documenting Ford's marriage, circa 1897-1900 (Box 25)
  - Emily E. Ford obituaries, 1893 (Box 25)
  - Condolence letters to Paul Leicester Ford on his mother's passing, 1893 (Box 25)
  - "Cupid's Insurrection, a comedy in three acts, by Paul Leicester Ford," typescript (Box 25)
  - "Evening Post Articles," bound volume of clippings, 1887 (Box 25)
  - "Pratt Institute Monthly", 1893 September (Box 25)
  - "1814. New London. Pettypaug Point" (Brooklyn, NY: Privately Printed, 1881) (Box 25)
  - Reproductions of Allen Gilbert drawings (Box 25)
  - "A Summary View of the Rights of British America", 1892 (Box 25)
  - Yorktown - collected printed material (Box 25)
  - "Books that have helped me," autograph manuscript (Box 26)
  - Janice Meredith waltzes - sheet music, [1900] (Box 26)
  - "The Ladies Home Journal", 1900 July (Box 26)
  - Webster Genealogy. Compiled and Printed for Presentation Only by Noah Webster. New Haven. 1836. With Notes and Corrections by his Great-Grandson, Paul Leicester Ford. (Brooklyn, NY: Privately Printed, 1876) (Box 27)
    2 copies
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, documents, and ephemera, 2 (Box 27)
  - Portrait of Paul Leicester Ford by L. V. O'Ryan, undated; Oil on canvas, 73.5 x 65.8 cm., framed (Box 33 (art))
  - Miniature portraits of Ford, 1906, undated; 2 miniatures (Box 30)
    2 miniature portraits of Paul Leicester Ford: one as a baby, in oval case with lock of hair; the other, created posthumously in 1906 by A. L. Eckardt, watercolor on ivory, oval, framed
  - Minature portrait of "Janice Meredith" by L.V. O'Ryan, 1 miniature, watercolor on ivory, oval, framed (Box 30)
  - Portrait of Noah Webster by Samuel F. B. Morse, [1823]; Oil on canvas, 84.7 x 72.7 cm., framed (Box 31 (art))
  - Portrait of Rebecca Greenleaf Webster by Jared Bradley Flagg, [circa 1840]; Oil on canvas, 84.7 x 72.7 cm., framed (Box 32 (art))
- Oversize Materials, 2; 0.33 linear feet
  - Newspaper clippings (in Series III), 1896-1900; 2 (Box 28 (Oversize))
  - Periodicals containing articles about Ford (in Series IV), 1890-1897 (Box 28 (Oversize))
  - Orchestra parts for unspecified dramatic production, manuscript (in Series IV) (Box 28 (Oversize))
  - The Trial of Elizabeth Duchess Dowager of Kingston for Bigamy, Before the Right Honourable The House of Peers, in Westminster-Hall in Full Parliament. London: Printed for Charles Bathurst, in Fleet-Street, 1776 (in Series IV), 1776 April 15 (Box 28 (Oversize))
  - Posters: publicity for novels and plays (in Series IV) (Box 29 (Oversize))